Guide to the Tom Law San Francisco Bay Area Punk and Rock Handbill and Poster Collection M1976
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Tom Law San Francisco Bay Area Punk and Rock Handbill and Poster Collection
1981-1989
bulk
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Law, Tom
M1976
2.5 Linear Feet: 1154 posters and 2 magazines in 3 manuscript boxes, 2 flat boxes and 1 large map folder
The Tom Law San Francisco Bay Area Punk and Rock Handbill and Poster Collection features over 1100 posters collected in San Francisco between 1981 and 1986. This street art chronicles the musical and cultural history of the San Francisco Bay Area in the mid-eighties. The majority of fliers are advertisements for local and touring bands, but posters for readings, screenings, plays, art openings, political protests, and even lost pets are also present.
Access to Collection
The materials are open for research use.
Acquisition Information
This collection was purchased by Stanford University, Special Collections in August 2013.
Biography
Thomas James Law was born in 1943 and was in his forties when he collected these posters. Originally from St. Paul, Minnesota, Law moved to San Francisco in about 1981. He lived in the Tenderloin in 1983 and relocated to the Upper Haight a year later. On his regular walks around the city, he began to take notice of the distinct and vibrant posters stapled and taped to virtually every public surface. Curiously, Law never went to any of the events advertised, only recognizing a certain aesthetic value in the fliers themselves. "I liked the images. I liked the names. They suggested something different. They were new concepts: lyrical and wild. I never heard their music or saw them perform. I didn't care to: I just wanted their posters."
Law began carefully removing the frequently worn and weather-beaten fliers and handbills from telephone poles and kiosks. "Usually it was possible to remove them with a knife, a key, a piece of glass." In this manner, Law gathered posters representing many kinds of activity in San Francisco, unbeholden to one scene or another. "Despite their variety they all have one thing in common: they caught my eye." Law was admittedly more of a classic rock fan. Among his favorites were the Rolling Stones, David Bowie, and Dire Straits. Nevertheless, he became increasingly systematic in gathering fliers by particular bands. "After awhile I looked forward to finding additional posters of certain groups."
Some posters also bear evidence of having been reposted; like other collectors, "my room on Haight Street had been covered from floor to ceiling with these posters." In 1986 he moved to Berlin and ceased all collecting activity, outside of a few he gathered in Minneapolis in 1989. Tom Law passed away in 2002.
All quotes are taken from his text accompanying a small exhibition in Germany in 1999.
Scope
The collection contains over 1100 posters, fliers and handbills, several in multiple copies in varying colors and condition. Often they are stuck together, fragmented, or partially illegible. Most posters conform to the standardized paper sizes of 8.5x11, 8.5x17 or 11x14 inches. Some are professionally typeset and designed, others are hand drawn and cheaply photocopied. Very few of the fliers are credited to an artist or designer, but it can be assumed they were often made by the artists or bands themselves. If there are listings for other events at the same venue, however, it is likely that the club produced the poster. The work of notable illustrators such as Raymond Pettibon, Marc Rude and Shawn Kerri (as well as gay erotica artist Tom of Finland) is used on a handful of fliers. Any credits when present have been transcribed, but many are initials or abbreviations.
The earliest poster in the collection can be dated to 1981, but the majority are from between 1983 and 1986. There are also a small number of fliers from Minneapolis in 1989. Although there are many kinds of posters here, the majority are gig fliers for independent music. These bands for the most part played alternative rock, punk, metal, goth/death rock, garage, psychedelia, experimental, worldbeat, reggae, or a hybrid of different styles. There are fliers from relatively well-known groups early in their careers, including Faith No More, Primus, Camper Van Beethoven, American Music Club, The Ophelias, and Chris Isaak. However, the following list of local bands, more or less in order of frequency, are most represented in the collection:
The Looters, Slovenly, Too Much Fun, The Whitefronts, Until December, The Morlocks, Shy Hands, My Sin, Mrs. Green, Terra Incognita, The Naked Into, The Cat Heads, 7 Dutch Poets, Flying Color, Frightwig, Glorious Din, Impulse F, The Invertebrates, The Witnesses, Ku Ku Ku, Jet Boy, The Sea Hags, Mapenzi, Paranoid Blue, Shiva Dancing, Zulu Spear, Crawl Away Machine, Blue Movie, Defectors, Housecoat Project, House Of Wheels, Helios Creed, Boss Hoss, Caroliner Rainbow, Club Foot Orchestra, Mess Tent, Mudwomen, Tragic Mulatto, Pig Latin, Pleasant Day, Short Dogs Grow, Spot 1019, Victim's Family, Wages Of Sin, Whorl, Stick Against Stone, Three Mouse Guitars, Typhoon, and Tripod Jimmie.
Some of the more colorful and provocative fliers come from the many punk, hardcore and skate rock shows during this period, with bands such as D.R.I. (Dirty Rotten Imbeciles), The Dicks, M.D.C. (at the time, Millions of Dead Cops), Social Unrest, The Afflicted, Christ On Parade, Condemned To Death, Clown Alley, Crucifix, Morally Bankrupt, Black Athletes, Noize Boyz, The Sluglords, Special Forces, and Verbal Abuse. Fliers for metal bands such as Sacrilege, Mordred, Death, and Possessed, and goth rock groups Altar De Fey, Fade To Black, and Our Lady Of Pain are equally eye-catching. In general, there are fewer fliers from touring bands, perhaps because they were less able to post fliers in advance of shows. Due to more active promoter involvement, many touring fliers are for punk shows featuring bands such as Black Flag, Redd Kross, R.K.L., The Butthole Surfers, The Offenders, and Toxic Reasons (who actually lived in San Francisco during the time). The more established San Francisco punk bands were also frequently on tour throughout this period, and the collection contains unexpectedly few fliers from the Dead Kennedys, Flipper, and M.D.C. Of course, their popularity also meant that fans would have removed their posters before Law had a chance. Some of the more offensive bands and fliers may have been also been taken down quickly.
These clubs were most frequently listed on fliers: Mabuhay Gardens, On Broadway, Stone, Club Vis a Vis (i.e. the VIS), 16th Note, Full Moon Saloon, Club 181, Graffiti, I-Beam, Nightbreak, Oasis, Farm, Club Foot, and Sound of Music. There are four rarely seen fliers for hardcore shows at Valencia Tool & Die. Venues in the East Bay that advertised in San Francisco include Oakland's Ruthie's Inn and the New Method Warehouse in Emeryville.
Other spaces for public art events include the Martin/Weber Gallery, San Francisco Art Institute, Artists Television Access, The Lab, Beef Gallery, Valencia Rose, and Theatre Rhinoceros. These fliers belong to a critical period of development in multimedia and video art, performance and comedy, and should not be overlooked despite the title of the collection.
The collection also contains two small San Francisco music magazines, "Wiring Department" and "O+"O, with coverage of many of the same groups on the fliers.
Collection Contents
Item-level description has been provided in the form of a spreadsheet hosted by Stanford University's Digital Repository. Here one may find controlled data on the names, places, and dates printed on every flier in the collection. The spreadsheet, along with informal photographs of selected fliers, can be viewed or downloaded here: http://purl.stanford.edu/yx763wc107.
Arrangement
Outside of grouping most duplicates, the collection's original order (more or less randomly by size) has been retained.
Recommended Reading
Belsito, Peter, and Bob Davis. Hardcore California: A History of Punk and New Wave. Berkeley, CA: Last Gasp of San Francisco, 1983.
Boulware, Jack, and Silke Tudor. Gimme Something Better: The Profound, Progressive, and Occasionally Pointless History of Bay Area Punk from Dead Kennedys to Green Day. Penguin, 2009.
Bowles, Murray. If Life Is A Bowl of Cherries, What Am I Doing In The Pit? Berkeley, CA: Maximum Rock n' Roll, 1986.
Burleigh, Victor. Great Rock & Roll Street Art. Atglen, PA: Schiffer Pub, 2004.
Burleigh, Victor. Great Street Art: Reggae, Blues, and World Beat Posters, 1977-1989. Atglen, PA: Schiffer Pub, 2006.
Ensminger, David A. Visual Vitriol: The Street Art and Subcultures of the Punk and Hardcore Generation. Jackson Miss.: University Press of Mississippi, 2011.
Turcotte, Bryan R., and Christopher T. Miller. Fucked Up + Photocopied: Instant Art of the Punk Rock Movement. Corte Madera, Calif: Gingko Press, 1999.
Rock music -- California -- San Francisco -- 1981-1990 -- Posters.; Posters -- California -- San Francisco.; Music -- California -- San Francisco; Street art -- California -- San Francisco; Fliers (Printed matter); Law, Tom
- Posters, 3 manuscript boxes, 2 flat boxes and 1 large map folder
  Scope and Contents
  For a detailed inventory of names, places, and dates on the posters, please refer to the spreadsheet available here: https://stacks.stanford.edu/file/druid:yx763wc1075/M1976%20Tom%20Law_item%20description.xlsx
  - Folder 1, 1984- 1986 (Box 1)
    The materials consist of the following posters:
    1. Jack Daniels Nite and Comedy!; 9th St. & Howard St., San Franscisco, CA; December 5th and 6th, 1984; 4x8.
    2. Perfect Strangers; Club 181; 181 Eddy St., San Francisco, CA; 1983-05-14; 5.5x8.5.
    3. Mordred, Death, Rhythm Pigs, Second Shadow, Armageddon Light Company; The Farm; 1499 Potrero Ave. San Francisco, CA; 1985-12-13; 5.5x8.5.
    4. Hunting Lodge (from Michigan), Gerechtigkeits Liga (from Germany), Problemist; Lab, The [Co-Lab]; 1805 Divisadero St. San Francisco, CA; 1984-11-16; 5.5x8.5.
    5. UFA, Typhoon, Blue Movie, The Whitefronts; Nightbreak; 1821 Haight St. San Francisco, CA; 1986-04-02; 5.5x8.5.
    6. The Ophelias, Shiva Burlesque; V.I.S. Club; 628 Divisadero St. San Francisco, CA; 1986-03-08; 4x5.5.
    7. Open Heart Invitational Show; Beef Gallery; 659 Haight St. San Francisco, CA; February 13; 5.5x8.5.
    8. Teggan Coussell, Nancy Byrne; Bibliomantic Book Gallery; Haight St. Near Fillmore St. San Francisco, CA; April 1; 7x8.5.
    9. Dream Weaver,Janus Janice Aurah Karmah Kramer, Kozmick Ladye; San Francisco, CA.
    10. The Nashville Ramblers (from San Diego); Mabuhay Gardens; 443 Broadway San Francisco, CA; 1986-02-15; 8.5x3.5.
    11. Toxic Reasons, M.I.A., Whipping Boy, Special Forces; The Farm; 1499 Potrero Ave. San Francisco, CA; 1985-03-01; 4.5x5.5.
    12. No Business As Usual Mass Induction; 8th St. & Fulton San Francisco, CA; 8.5x7.
    13. [uncredited illustrations of animals in clothes, including a mouse on a skateboard], 8.5x6.
    14. Kommunity FK; The Farm; 1499 Potrero Ave. San Francisco, CA; 1986-05-01 [?]; 5.5x8.5.
    15. The Dicks, D.R.I., Jungle Studs, The Morlocks, Sea Hags, The Weasels; The Farm; 1499 Potrero Ave. San Francisco; 1985-08-23; 6x8.5.
  - Folder 2, 1982- 1986 (Box 1)
    1. John Heartfield, Zero For Conduct; Media [Mad Movies At Media]; 360 9th St. San Francisco, CA; 1986-05-03; 6x8.5.
    2. Zapp, Juicy, Dana Dane & Whistle; San Jose Civic Auditorium; 135 W. San Carlos St. San Jose, CA; 1986-04-12; 5.5x8.5.
    3. Davenports, Jackals, The Cat Heads; Mabuhay Gardens; 443 Broadway San Francisco, CA; 1985-06-26; 5.5x8.5.
    4. Calico Basket, Test Subjects [Pest Subjects], Pleasant Day, Pukes; Club Foot; 2520 3rd St. San Francisco, CA; 1985-10-25; 4x11.
    5. UFA (D. Ellman, H. Stein), Boroni (S. Pocock), Set/Window - Janice Nyman; Beef Gallery; 659 Haight St. San Francisco, CA; 1982-05-27; 5.5x8.5.
    6. Us Girls; The Oasis; 298 11th St. San Francisco, CA; 1984-08-08; 5.5x8.5.
    7. Too Much Fun; Full Moon Saloon; 1725 Haight St. San Francisco, CA; 1986-01-09; 4x11.
    8. The Naked Into, Blue Movie; V.I.S. Club; 628 Divisadero St. San Francisco, CA; July 4, 7.5x9.
    9. The Naked Into, Blue Movie, Mrs. Green; The Farm; 1499 Potrero Ave. San Francisco, CA; 1985-08-16 -- The Naked Into, John Cale; The Stone; 412 Broadway San Francisco, CA; 1985-08-11; 8.5x7.
    10. John Heartfield, Zero For Conduct; Media [Mad Movies At Media]; 360 9th St. San Francisco, CA; 1986-05-03; 6x8.5.
    11. Rhythm Pigs, Clown Alley; On Broadway; 435 Broadway San Francisco, CA; January 29, 5.5x8.5.
    12. Impulse F; The Oasis; 298 11th St. San Francisco, CA; 1985-06-25; 5.5x4.5
    13. Permanent Wave; On Broadway; 435 Broadway San Francisco, CA; 1982-11-03; 5.5x8.5.
    14. The Refugees; Chi Chi Club; 440 Broadway San Francisco, CA; 1985-12-11; 10x6.
  - Folder 3, 1984- 1986 (Box 1)
    1. Stiffs; [Mabuhay Gardens?]; [443 Broadway?] San Francisco, CA; 8.5x11
    2. Faith No More, Glorious Din; Graffiti; 853 Valencia St. San Francisco, CA; 8.5x11.
    3. Sweat! A Beer Bust. $5 Donation, 10% To The SF AIDS Fund; Chaps; 11th St. & Harrison St. San Francisco, CA; 1985-06-23; 8.5x11.
    4. The Looters, Unruly World, Tricobra; The Farm; 1499 Potrero Ave. San Francisco, CA; 1985-10-05; 7x10.5.
    5. No Hands!; 8.5x11.
    6. The Blazing Redheads; Bay Brick Inn; 1190 Folsom St. San Francisco, CA; 1986-04-27; 8.5x11 -- The Blazing Redheads; El Rio; 3158 Mission St. San Francisco, CA; 1986-04-20; 8.5x11.
    7. Reward $500 For The Return Of A Wedding Ring Stolen From A Chinese Woman on Jan. 6, 1985; San Francisco CA; 1985; 8.5x11.
    8. Alien Sex Fiend; On Broadway; 435 Broadway San Francisco CA; 1984-03-07; 8.5x11.
    9.Robert Seidler; The Stone; 412 Broadway San Francisco, CA; 1986-04-10; 8.5x11.
    10.Wages Of Sin; Full Moon Saloon; 1725 Haight St. San Francisco, CA; 1985-10-17; 8.5x11.
    11. Adam Bomb, Jet Boy; Wolfgang's; 901 Columbus Ave. San Francisco, CA; 1984-06-04; 8.5x11.
    12. Primus, Slovenly; Graffiti; 853 Valencia St. San Francisco, CA; 1985-05-11; 8.5x11.
    13. The Dicks, The Morlocks, Jungle Studs, Sea Hags, The Weasels; The Farm; 1499 Potrero Ave. San Francisco, CA; 1985-08-23; 8.5x11.
    14. Agent Orange, Screamin' Sirens, Sea Hags; The Farm; 1499 Potrero Ave. San Francisco, CA; 1985-07-12; 8.5x11.
  - Folder 4, 1982- 1986 (Box 1)
    1. The Dicks, Morally Bankrupt, Slovenly, Ruin; Victoria Theatre; 2961 16th St. San Francisco, CA; 1984-12-31; 8.5x11.
    2. Redd Kross, The Dicks, Nip Drivers; Mabuhay Gardens; 443 Broadway San Francisco, CA; 1984-02-04 -- Angry Samoans, The Minutemen, The Afflicted; Ribzy; Mabuhay Gardens; 443 Broadway San Francisco, CA; 1984-02-18, 8.5x11.
    3. Fang, D.R.I, Gang Green, The Boneless One; Ruthie's Inn; 2618 San Pablo Ave. Berkeley, CA; August 3, 8.5x11.
    4. Sun Ra; Elite Club; 1805 Geary Blvd. San Francisco, CA; 1982-10-17; 8.5x11.
    5. Black Flag, S.W.A.; The Farm; 1499 Potrero Ave. San Francisco, CA; 1985-08-30; 8.5x11.
    6. Black Flag, Code Of Honor, Redd Kross, Nig-Heist; On Broadway; 435 Broadway San Francisco, CA; 1982-12-19 -- Black Flag, Flipper, Redd Kross; On Broadway; 435 Broadway San Francisco, CA; 1982-12-20; 8.5x11.
    7. Sonic Youth; Tupelo Chain Sex; Slovenly; The Stone; 412 Broadway San Francisco, CA; 1985-08-17; 8.5x11.
    8. The Necros, Social Unrest, Stalag 13, N.O.T.A., Teenage Warning; Ruthie's Inn; 2618 San Pablo Ave. Berkeley, CA; 1984-08-11; 8.5x11.
    9. Ugly Stick; Sound Of Music; 162 Turk St. San Francisco, CA; 8.5x11.
    10. Ugly Stick, Wax Headed Cricket Men; V.I.S. Club; 628 Divisadero St. San Francisco, CA; 1986-04-02; 8.5x11.
    11. The Mais, 7 Dutch Poets; V.I.S. Club; 628 Divisadero St. San Francisco, CA; 1986-04-18; 8.5x9.
    12. Leaving The Planet Sale! A Lifetime Collection! San Francisco, CA; 8.5x11.
  - Folder 5, 1984- 1986 (Box 1)
    1. The Mary Club, Three Women, Prey; Footwork Studio; 3221 22nd St. San Francisco, CA; 1986-05; 8.5x11.
    2. Traditional Cuisine In A Tropical Setting. A Cuban Mexican Café; Cha Cha Cha; San Francisco, CA; 8.5x11.
    3. We are God. God Is Good. You Are Good. There Is No Hell. [etc.]; 8.5x11.
    4. Art In Space. Video At The Eye Gallery. A Screening Of New Video Artworks From Earth; Eye Gallery; 758 Valencia St. San Francisco, CA; 1986-04-26; 8.5x11.
    5. San Francisco Psychedelic Rock Posters. Slides & Commentary by Walter Medeiros; Fort Mason Center. Building 2; 2 Marina Blvd. San Francisco, CA; November 7; 8.5x11.
    6. Pig Latin, Spot 1019, 3 Mouse Guitars, The Leopard Set, Ju Ju Box, Danny Williams (Comedian); The Farm; 1499 Potrero Ave. San Francisco, CA; 1986-02-21; 8.5x11.
    7. Tex & The Horseheads, Housecoat Project, Party Drivers; Mabuhay Gardens; 443 Broadway San Francisco, CA; 1985-09-27; 8.5x11.
    8. Denim TV; The Oasis; 298 11th St. San Francisco, CA; 1985-09-17; 8.5x11.
    9. Donna At The Turntables; Club 181; 181 Eddy St. San Francisco, CA; 1983-05- 18; 8.5x11.
    10. Nighteye; Mabuhay Gardens; 443 Broadway San Francisco, CA; 1984-09-27; 8.5x11.
    11. DJ Lebowitz; Caribbean Rose; 1039 Ocean Ave. San Francisco, CA; 1986-03-25; 8.5x11.
    12. Blue Stucco; Ashkenaz; 1317 San Pablo Ave. Berkeley, CA; 1986-04; 8.5x11.
    13. The Murmurs, Bonnie Hayes; Last Day Saloon; 406 Clement St. San Francisco, CA; May 3; 8.5x11.
  - Folder 6, 1984- 1986 (Box 1)
    1. Great Divide; V.I.S. Club; 628 Divisadero St. San Francisco, CA; August 2; 8.5x11.
    2. Damen Die Lieden (Our Lady of Pain); Fade To Black; Nightbreak; 1821 Haight St. San Francisco, CA; 1984-01-28; 8.5x11.
    3. P. Zuzu & K. Komo, Funhouse (from San Jose); Hotel Utah; 584 4th St. San Francisco, CA; 1984-08-18; 8.5x11.
    4. Proud Ones; Sound Of Music; 162 Turk St. San Francsico, CA; May 20; 8.5x11.
    5. Eyes Of God; Nightbreak; 1821 Haight St. San Francisco, CA; 1985-08-02; 8.5x11.
    6. Practical Dreamers; Graffiti; 853 Valencia St. San Francisco, CA; September 25 -- Practical Dreamers; Chi Chi Club; 440 Broadway San Francisco, CA; September 4 -- Practical Dreamers; Mabuhay Gardens; 443 Broadway San Francisco, CA; August 29; 8.5x11.
    7. 84 Rooms, Whiskey Worms; Hotel Utah; 584 4th St. San Francisco, CA; 1986-01-03; 8.5x11.
    8. The Nice Boys from New York; Ruthie's Inn; 2618 San Pablo Ave. Berkeley, CA; 1985-05-10 -- The Nice Boys from New York; Chi Chi Club; 440 Broadway San Francisco, CA; 1985-05-09; 8.5x11.
    9. 84 Rooms, Whiskey Worms; Hotel Utah; 584 4th St. San Francisco, CA; 1986-01-03; 8.5x11.
    10. Electric Koels; Untold Fables; Yard Trauma; V.I.S. Club; 628 Divisadero St. San Francisco, CA; 1986-01-03; 8.5x11.
    11. Elliot Schneider and The Banned; 16th Note; 3160 16th St. San Francisco, CA; 1986-03-20; 8.5x11.
    12. The Donners, 28th Day, The McGuires; V.I.S. Club; 628 Divisadero St. San Francisco, CA; 1986-04-17; 8.5x11.
    13. Dynatones; The Oasis; 298 11th St. San Francisco, CA; September 1; 8.5x11.
  - Folder 7, 1984- 1986 (Box 1)
    1. Short Dogs Grow, Verbal Abuse; New Method Warehouse; 3623 Adeline St. Emeryville, CA; January 31 -- Short Dogs Grow, Schrödinger's Cat; 16th Note; 3160 16th St. San Francisco, CA; February 6 -- Short Dogs Grow, Rhythm Pigs, Spot 1019; Hotel Utah; 584 4th St. San Francisco, CA; February 15 -- Short Dogs Grow, Noize Boyz, The Hot Combs; Hotel Utah; 584 4th St. San Francisco, CA; January 18 -- Short Dogs Grow, Helios Creed, Half Blind; Hotel Utah; 584 4th St. San Francisco, CA; 1986-01-25; 8.5x11.
    2. Scratch Break Hip Hop Funk; The Stud; 1535 Folsom St. San Francisco, CA; Mondays; 8.5x11.
    3. Slovenly; Vomit Launch; The Idiot; V.I.S. Club; 628 Divisadero St. San Francisco, CA; 1986-05-15; 8.5x11.
    4. See Page II; Chi Chi Club; 440 Broadway San Francisco, CA; 1985-12-14; 8.5x11.
    5. Shocking U, My Sin; V.I.S. Club; 628 Divisadero St. San Francisco, CA; 1986-04-26; 8.5x11.
    6. Until December; The Oasis; 298 11th St. San Francisco, CA; March 3; 8.5x11.
    7. P. Zuzu & K. Komo, Group Six; Hotel Utah; 584 4th St. San Francisco, CA; 1984-07-28; 8.5x11.
    8. The Raunch Hands; V.I.S. Club; 628 Divisadero St. San Francisco, CA; May 8; 8.5x11.
    9. Psychic Waiters; Chi Chi Club; 440 Broadway San Francisco, CA; 1985-02-21; 8.5x11.
    10. The Nice Boys From New York; The Oasis; 298 11th St. San Francisco, CA; October 8; 8.5x11.
    11. Ten Tall Men; Berkeley Square; 1333 University Ave. Berkeley, CA; 1986-01-14; 8.5x11.
    12. Rick Mills & Friends; Valencia Rose; 766 Valencia St. San Francisco, CA; November 16; 8.5x11.
    13. Rhythm Pigs; V.I.S. Club; 628 Divisadero St. San Francisco, CA; 1985-06-25; 8.5x11.
  - Folder 8, 1984- 1986 (Box 1)
    1. Spot 1019, Ugly Americans, The Front, Victim's Family, Christ On Parade; New Method Warehouse; 3623 Adeline St. San Francisco, CA; 1985-12-22; 8.5x11.
    2. Shy Hands; Nightbreak; 1821 Haight St. San Francisco, CA; 1985-07-25; 8.5x11.
    3. Subject To Change; Club 181; 181 Eddy St. San Francisco, CA; August 25; 8.5x11.
    4. Shy Hands; V.I.S. Club; 628 Divisadero St. San Francisco, CA; June 1; 8.5x11.
    5. Wombat Suicide; Graffiti; 853 Valencia St. San Francisco, CA 1984-07-05; 8.5x11.
    6. Sleepers, American Music Club; On Broadway; 435 Broadway San Francisco, CA; 1985-12-20; 8.5x11.
    7. Swelele, Out O' Grass Posse, Daddy Goalie; V.I.S. Club; 628 Divisadero St. San Francisco, CA; 1985-12-20 -- Swelele, Out O' Grass Posse, Fari Force Featuring Raskidus; V.I.S. Club; 628 Divisadero St. San Francisco, CA; 1985-12-21; 8.5x11.
    8. The Tenants; Full Moon Saloon; 1725 Haight St. San Francisco, CA; 1985-08-29; 8.5x11.
    9. Tragic Mulatto, Schrödinger's Cat, Pleasant Day; Club Foot; 2520 3rd St. San Francisco, CA; 1986-01-10; 8.5x11.
    10. Silent Night, Wages Of Sin, Shiva Dancing; Mabuhay Gardens; 443 Broadway San Francisco, CA; 1986-01-25; 8.5x11.
    11. Uh-Oh; The Q.T.; 1312 Polk St. San Francisco, CA; December 14 -- Uh-Oh; The Q.T.; 1312 Polk St. San Francisco, CA; December 26 -- Uh-Oh, Wink, Desprate Voices; Chi Chi Club; 440 Broadway San Francisco, CA; December 19; 8.5x11.
    12. Wages Of Sin; V.I.S. Club; 628 Divisadero St. San Francisco, CA; 1986-01-10; 8.5x11.
    13. The Whitefronts; The Cat Heads; Hotel Utah; 584 4th St. San Francisco, CA; 1986-01-04; 8.5x11.
  - Folder 9, 1982- 1986 (Box 1)
    1. The 12 Year Olds, Davenports, Party Drivers; Club Foot; 2520 3rd St. San Francisco, CA; November 1; 8.5x11.
    2. The Afflicted; San Francisco Civic Center; 99 Grove St. San Francisco, CA; 1984-02-18; 8.5x11.
    3. Too Much Fun, The Edge; Cotati Cabaret; Cotati, CA -- Too Much Fun; Mapenzi; Mabuhay Gardens; 443 Broadway, San Francisco, CA; 1985-03-23; 9.5x7.5.
    4. Paul Kantner; Marty Balin; Jack Casady; Slick Aguilar; Tim Gorman; Barry Lowenthal; Keith Crossan [Jefferson Starship], The Uptones, Rahni Raines; The Filmore; 1805 Geary Blvd San Francisco, CA; December 7; 8.5x11.
    5. Carmaig de Forest, Impulse F; Berkeley Square; 1333 University Ave. Berkeley, CA; 1985-05-08; 8.5x11.
    6. Breather "Earth Inferno", Deviation Social (performance and screening of The Birth & Death Of Meaning"), Consternation of Pain; Martin/Weber Gallery; 220 8th St. San Francisco, CA; October 26; 8.5x11.
    7. Out of The Blue; Cedar Cinema; 38 Cedar St. San Francisco, CA; May 31, June 1; 8.5x11.
    8. DJ [unnamed]; Buzzby's; 1436 Polk St. San Francisco, CA; 8.5x11.
    9. Monica Palacios; Valencia Rose; 766 Valencia St. San Francisco, CA; 1983-05-21; 8.5x11.
    10. Eat Chicken At The Eagle. To Benefit: The Kaposi's Sarcoma Foundation; Eagle Tavern; 12th St. & Harrison St. San Francisco, CA; 1982-11-21; 8.5x11.
    11. Proposition: Epic Poetry Perspective 7. Also: Open Poetry Reading; Café Picaro; 3120 16th St. San Francisco, CA; 1984-08-19; 8.5x11.